《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》 前情提要
APOLLO: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
我感觉我在放弃我的职责
I feel like I'm abandoning my post.
是时候打包了  少  你明白我的意思
It's time to pack it in, Saul. You know it.
超过半数的船员下去新卡布里卡了
TIGH: More than half the crew's down on New Caprica already.
这里真的没有太多东西需要我做了
I'm not really doing too much up here anymore.
祝你好运
Good luck.
噢  天呀  是赛昂舰队!  他们发现我们了
Oh, my Gods. It's the Cylon Fleet. They found us.
你们也该知道这次任务只能以一种方式结束
There's only one way that this mission ends,
那就是从新卡布里卡
and that's with the successful rescue
成功营救我们的人民
of our people off of New Caprica.
你把他们都带回来了  少
You brought them home, Saul.
不是所有人
Not all of them.
我们怎么办?
What about us?
不会再有我们两个字了  行不?
There is no "us," all right?
这里已经什么都没有了
There is nothing here.
你明白没有?  什么都没有
Do you get that? Nothing!
李  你准备何时给自己找个女友?
Lee, when are you gonna get yourself a girl?
我会的  谢谢
I'm doing fine, thank you.
你还是没和小杜搞上  对吗?
You're not still frakking Dualla, are you?
我以与你共事为荣  中尉
I am proud to serve with you, Lieutenant,
也以你为我的妻子为荣
and to call you my wife.
我现在处在不同的立场
STARBUCK: I'm in a different place now.
我只想狠扁一个人 而那人最好是你
I just want to hurt someone, and it might as well be you.
这正是我想要的
That was exactly what I needed.
很高兴我的服务能让您满意
Glad to be of service.
该死的
Damn it.
找这个吗?
Looking for this?
是的
Yeah.
卡拉
Kara,
我想要你做个真正的你
I want you back.
我想要我们的婚姻回来 我的意思是真正的婚姻
I want our marriage back, I want a real marriage.
那如果我还没有准备好去面对呢?
And what if I'm just not ready for that?
我不知道 那我猜你可能永远做不到的
I don't know, then I guess it'll never be.
也许  毕竟我不是你真正要的人
Maybe 'cause I'm not what you really want after all.
我舞会迟到了
I'm late for the dance.
别忘了你靠在门口的靴子  山米
Don't forget your boots on the way out, Sammy.
你行的   李!   加油
KAT: Get your right up, Lee! Come on!
看不出阿格森很能打嘛
If it isn't the Fighting Agathons, huh?
星芭  你又和往常一样迟到
Starbuck, late to the party as usual.
至少我及时看到你教训空军指挥官了
At least I got here in time to watch you kick the CAG's ass.
李 打得不错 小心右路
KAT: Lee, You got it, slick him right up.
他打得很凶  我会利用这点
He's a tough little frakker, I'll give him that.
他在戏弄我 似乎以为胜券在握
He's playing me like he's got it in for me.
-别管了 -好的
- ATHENA: Stay off the ropes. - All right.
采取行动 别管任何事情
KAT: Make your move. Just stay off the ropes.
好了  开始
All right, you got him!
加油 李 教训他
KAT: Come on, Lee, kick his ass! You got him! You got him!
加油
Come on!
西洛！加油 伙计
MAN: Helo! Come on, man!
妈的 加油 李
KAT: Damn it, come on, Lee!
好吧，看那个
Well, look at that.
几个月前 你根本没法叫他上拳击台的
A couple months ago, you would have had to roll him into this ring.
对 不再如此了
Well, not anymore.
如果头脑冷静的话 他还有机会
You know, with a cooler head, he might have half a chance.
用你的左手！ 加油！ 盯着他
KAT: Use your left! Come on! Watch him.
加油 西洛！
Come on, Helo!
二…
two,
三…
three,
四…
four,
五…
five,
六…
six,
七
seven.
嘿  嘿  好了 看着我
Hey, hey, hey. All right, look at me.
你赢了 宝贝
You did it, baby.
费希尔 费希尔 你上了
Fischer. Fischer, you're up.
打得不错
You did fine.
被这样打就让你吃不消了  对吧?
Bit off a little more than you could chew, huh?
噢  拜托  李  别那样
Come on, Lee. Don't be that way.
别走啊 晚会才开始
Stick around, the night's young.
哦 那你玩好 我得失陪了
Well, I guess then you'll just have to enjoy it without me.
那么快就气馁了?
Pulling your tags out so soon?
我完了  卡拉
I'm done, Kara.
我还没有
I'm not.
那现在是哪位会让你吃不消呢  上尉?
Now who's biting off more than they can chew, Captain?
不会是我被打倒的  少校
Not me, from where I'm standing, Major.
让开
Excuse me.
我不敢相信他们的进度这么快
Can't believe the progress they've made.
一个月以前跟现在完全不一样
You should've seen it a month ago.
嗯  相比这种到处都是垃圾的地方
But I'd still rather sleep in a warm bunk every night
我情愿每晚睡在暖和的军舰铺位上
than muck around in this muck.
今晚的床位会很暖和的
Bunk's gonna be plenty warm tonight.
他同意了
He said yes.
他批准你调职了?
He approved the transfer?
你俩就不会保守点秘密  对吗?
STARBUCK: You two just don't know how to keep a secret, do you?
你们是不是准备和波塔尔一起扛起铁铲呢?
So, what, are you guys here to see Baltar put a shovel in the ground?
"参加我们建设美好明天的庆典"
"Join the celebration as we break ground for a better tomorrow. "
噢  有那么多的废话
Aw... That's such a load of crap.
会有一个露天酒吧
There's an open bar.
真的吗?  那你们干嘛不参加呢?
Really? See, now why didn't you say so?
李  你最好也表表态
Lee, you've got to let your better half do the talking for you.
她刚才说到点子上了
She gets right to the point.
让我们去见识下美好的"新明天"吧
Let's go find us a better tomorrow.
我们先走了
Excuse us.
没想到找到你的时候是在玩沙子
I didn't expect to find you playing in the sand.
那不是沙子
It's not sand.
那是冲积物 这里过去是河床
It's alluvial deposits. This used to be the river mouth.
那你得把鞋子脱下
And you just had to take off your shoes
才能在冲积物上玩
and play in the alluvial deposits.
多浪漫啊!
How romantic.
你衣服颜色真不错
That's a nice color on you.
谢谢
Thank you.
很高兴见到你  劳拉
It's good to see you, Laura.
我也是  比尔
You, too, Bill.
你也在这里
There you are!
嘿嘿  你好吗?
Hey, hey! How are you?
我父亲是个搏击迷呢
My father was an avid fight fan.
我很崇拜父亲  所以我也喜欢看精彩的搏击
I adored my father so I love a good fight.
我听说了你所谓的舞会了
I heard about your so-called dance.
是偶然听到的
Accidentally, I might add.
不是私人舞会
Don't take it personally.
这是士兵的传统
It's sort of a private tradition.
传统?
Tradition?
因为老是在军舰上待着会让人沮丧
There's a lot of frustration aboard warships.
争论会带来不合还会演化成仇恨
Arguments become grudges and end up being feuds.
这种形式可以让他们合理地释放压力
It allows them to let off some steam,
以公开的形式  大家都能参与
out in the open so everybody can participate.
不管是什么军衔 只要你把身份牌丢进箱子里
Rank doesn't matter. As long as you throw your tags in the box,
都能参加一个公平的比赛
everyone's fair game.
下一个出场的是热狗!
Next up is Hotdog!
热狗  把你的屁股挪上来  然后选个对手
Hotdog, get your bun up here and pick a partner.
你把身份牌扔进去了没有?
Did you throw your tags in there?
没有
No.
不 其实我想丢的
No. I wish,
我面对了太多压力
all the frustrations that I have.
谁是你的对手呢  热狗?
TIGH: Who's your partner, Hotdog?
星芭
Starbuck.
你一定是在和我开玩笑？
I cannot believe it.
星芭
KAT: Starbuck!
上  星芭!  他是你的了
Go, Starbuck. He's yours.
搞定他 星芭！
ATHENA: Get him, Starbuck!
加油！
Yeah! Go on!
起来！起来！
MAN 1: Come on! Come on!
就该这么打 星芭！
MAN 2: Way to go, Starbuck!
干得好
Here you go.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
让我们记住这一天 作为我们
Let this day be remembered as the day that we broke the ground
新的明天的奠基日
for our new tomorrow.
不  一切都会好起来的  对不对?
No, it gets better, okay?
因为到时候他们都会回衣帽间的
'Cause they come back to the locker room
会带上手铐  还有两根稻草杆!
with a set of handcuffs and some straw.
我有没有告诉你能和你结婚时我又多高兴
Did I ever tell you how glad I am I married you?
不只一次
Not once.
那好  我要搞个特殊的仪式来纪念一下
Well, then I'll save it for a special occasion.
过来
Come here.
- 嘿  甜心 - 嘿  宝贝
- Hey, honey. Hi. -Hey, baby.
我们将拥有能够
We'll have the infrastructure
应对任何突发事件的基本设施
to deal with any unforeseen circumstances...
抱歉 长官
Excuse me for just a moment.
财政部长刚走过去 我就来
The finance minister just came by, and I should really...
去吧
Go ahead.
噢  天啊  我想他都没离开休息过
Oh, my God. I thought he'd never leave.
他是个好小子
He's a good kid.
确实是
Indeed.
你说这种东西是当地产的吗?
You're saying this stuff grows around here?
在北面的山上  那儿有一个溪流
In the mountains north of here, there's this little stream
流到这个湖里
that comes down into this lake.
水非常清澈 像玻璃般的清透
The water's so clear, it's like looking through glass.
我想在那边建个小木屋
I'm thinking of building a cabin.
想法不错
It's good.
是不错
It is good.
漂亮的组合拳
That's a beautiful combination.
我错过了什么?
What did I miss?
菲戈斯基  你把战机修好了吗?
Figurski, you done that bird already?
没呢  是回转仪的麻烦
No, the damn gyro's giving me trouble.
拜托了  军士长  我是唯一还在那边的人
Come on, Chief, I'm the only one over there.
妈的!  自己去找点东西喝吧
Frak. Frak it, get yourself a drink.
船要沉啦  军士长?
Ship down, Chief?
对啊  明天再说了
Yeah, we'll get it tomorrow.
也该让他放松下了
I figured I'd give him a little R&R.
我得提前祝贺你
Congratulations. I may be jumping the gun,
在卡拉狄加上出生的第一个男孩
but first boy born on Galactica.
我就是为这事来找您的 长官
That's the thing I wanted to talk to you about, sir.
凯莉不想孩子出生在这里
Cally doesn't want him born here.
我也不想 毕竟他…
And neither do I. Not if he has a chance
有机会呼吸着新鲜的空气出生
to grow up breathing fresh air.
你要说什么
What are you saying?
谢谢
Thank you.
请允许让我们离开这里的岗位
Well, we both would like to request to be relieved of duty
去新卡布里卡定居
and resettle in New Caprica.
不行
No. No way.
这期间你们得呆在这里
Look, you're both here for the duration.
什么？
What?
你能帮我拿着吗?  谢谢
Can you hold these? Thank you.
军士长
Chief.
把你那又肥又大的屁股挪上来
Get your fat, lazy ass up here.
西洛
Helo.
绑紧点
Make them tight.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
他是个老头了 没事的
He's an old man. It'll be fine.
再说  他也不是认真的
He's not serious anyways.
真想打吗?
Sure about this?
是你要倒霉了
It's your funeral.
加油!  伙计
MAN: Yeah! Do it, buddy.
起来  军士长  我们才刚开始呢
Get up, Chief. We're just getting started.
我在想 或许…
You know, I was thinking it's probably better
还是在卡拉狄加上生小孩更好吧
to have a baby on Galactica anyways.
那里有医务室、医生、药品
You know, there's a sick bay, doctors, medicine.
不  这里会更好
Yeah. No, it'll be better.
我们也会更开心的
Yeah, we'll be happier.
没错
Yeah.
加油 上将！
Come on, Admiral!
- 嘿  甜心 - 嘿  宝贝
- Hey, honey. Hi. - Hey, baby.
是真的吗  比尔?
Is this really it, Bill?
我们要在这里这样度过余生吗?
Is this how we're going to spend all the rest of our days?
也许我们就这样享受就行了
maybe we should just enjoy this.
是的
I am.
不 不 我是指享受在这里的生活
No, no, I mean, enjoy being here
在这个星球上 能多久就多久
on this planet as long as it lasts.
也许赛昂人会找到我们  也许它们找不到
I mean, maybe the Cylons come back, maybe they don't.
但是现在我们要休息一下
But for now, right now, we've got a break.
我手下好多人想从战舰上下来 定居在这里
I've got people that want to get off the ship, move down here.
也不能责怪他们 你会怎么做?
Can't say as I blame them, I mean, what are you gonna do?
你就是这样对付敌人的吗  军士长?
Is this how you fight your enemies, Chief?
你就是这样为生活奋斗的?
Is this how you fight for your life?
别找借口 让我看看你像个战士的样子 起来!
No excuses. Show me you're a soldier. Get up.
打得好  上将!
Come on! Nice, Admiral!
这就是你想要的吗？这就是你想要的吗？上将
Is that what you want? Is that what you want, Admiral?
老头子打得不错
The old man's got chops.
他知道什么时候进攻 什么时候防守
He knows when to make his moves, when to hold back.
我真希望他儿子也学学他
I wish I could say the same for his son.
加油
Come on!
我带来更多的
I bring offerings.
真是时候 我喝的可是烈酒
Just in time. I was running on bingo fuel.
喔  看看那里
Wow, look at that.
你都把安德斯喝到桌底下去了
You literally drank Anders under the table.
小杜在哪?
Where's Dee?
她正在打包 准备走了
She packed it in to go pack.
那只剩下我们俩了
Guess it's just you and me then.
是啊  就剩下我们俩了
Yup, it's just you and me.
老爸  加油!
Come on, Dad!
不太好  已经够了  你该认输了
That's bad. That's enough already. You should quit.
把血止上就行了
Just stop the blood.
拿止血剂来消肿止血
Coagulant for the swelling as for the bleeding.
-拜托 -天啊
- Come on. - Gods damn it.
你还要坚持吗
You insist on doing this?
你还要打  你疯了吗?
You wanna do this, you're crazy, right?
-你真想继续打吗？ -是的
You wanna do this? Yeah.
那好  你要防守好  他要发狠了
All right. Keep your guard up, he's coming in wild,
你要用左勾拳还击 你想要赢吗?
get him with a left hook. You wanna win?
我赢不了的
I'm not gonna win.
当心他的直拳
You gotta watch his jab. Watch his jab.
他的直拳太狠了  听到了吗?
His jab's killing you, all right?
军士长  早上好  早上好  凯莉
Chief, Morning. Morning, Kelly.
我仔细考虑了你说的话
I've been thinking about what you said
一艘太空堡垒没地方养个家庭
A Battlestar's no place to raise a family.
我会想念你的  军士长
So I'm gonna miss you, Chief.
祝你好运
But I'm gonna wish you good luck.
谢谢你  长官
Thank you, sir.
衷心祝福你们
My best to both of you.
我们可以搬家了?  真的吗?
We're moving? Really?
谢谢你
Thank you.
我希望你俩将来至少生一打
I want you guys to have at least a dozen.
你会看到的
We'll see about that.
起来 我们帮你
Get up. We'll get you up.
当你们站在这个甲板上 你们就要作好战斗的准备
When you stand on this deck, you be ready to fight,
否则你就是质疑我们在里的原因
or you dishonor the reason why we're here.
请记住
And remember this.
当你在和某人战斗时  他就不再是你的朋友
When you fight a man, he's not your friend.
当你们领导别人的时候  也是一样的
The same goes when you lead men.
我曾经忽略过一次
I forgot that once.
我让你们都走得太近了 所有的人
I let you get too close. All of you.
我放松了自己的警惕
I dropped my guard.
我还让你们中的一些人休假去了
I gave some of you breaks,
允许你们当中一些人退役
let some of you go before the fight was really over.
我让这个团队 这个大家庭几乎分崩瓦解
I let this crew, and this family, disband.
我们为此付出了生命的代价
And we paid the price in lives.
我不会让这种事情再发生了
That can't happen again.
菲戈斯基 你跟我来
Figurski, you're with me.
让我们去把那架战机修好
Let's get that bird back on the line.
总统女士
Madam President.
上将
Admiral.
好了  这次"舞会"就此结束
All right. This dance is over.
带上你们的酒瓶 身份牌  都散了
Get your booze and your dog tags and let's get out of here.
怎么  你就这样结束了?
So what, you're just gonna call it?
今晚你还不够兴奋吗  上尉?
Not enough excitement for one night for you, Captain?
嗨 嗨
STARBUCK: Hey. Hey!
你他妈的想躲哪去?
Where the frak do you think you're going?
结束了  卡拉
It's over, Kara.
那又怎么样?
So what?
你有胆量勾搭另一个男人的女人
You have the guts to try and frak
却不敢和一个女人在拳台上较量？
another man's woman, but not to fight one?
小杜是否知道她的男人是个什么样的孬种
I wonder if Dee knew what she was getting.
觉得她会顺从这样的男人吗？
Think she would have settled for sloppy seconds?
真相很伤人  不是吗?
The truth stings, don't it?
你想较量一下吗  上尉？
You want a fight, Captain?
如你所愿
You've got it.
怎么 怕打到我
What? You afraid to hit me?
还是根本打不到?
Or maybe you can't.
看看 这块地方很适合盖间房子
Check it out. It's a great place for a house.
你真的决定不再飞了吗?
So, you're really gonna give up flying?
现在即使继续飞也没什么意思
Flying's gonna suck now anyway.
全都是没完没了的警戒巡逻
Lots of training, endless caps.
战争已经结束了 连同所有有意义的东西
War is over. So is all the good stuff.
给我介绍一下卡拉·安德斯未来的幸福生活
Give me a tour of the future life of Kara Anders.
我不会结婚的
I'm not getting married.
那么你所做的又都是为了什么呢  卡拉?
Well, then, what's the point, Kara?
我意思是  你确实爱他  对吧？
I mean, you love him, right?
为什么提这个  李?
Where are we going with this, Lee?
这就是问题所在  难道不是吗？
Well, now that's the question, isn't it?
我们到底要怎样下去?
Where are we going?
我的意思是  如果就这样了
I mean, what if this is it?
卡拉  你的余生
This, the rest of your life, Kara.
这真的是你想过的生活吗?
Is this how you want to spend it?
谁是你想相伴余生的人?
Who you want to spend it with?
怎么了
What's going on?
这是在干嘛
What's it look like?
看上去他们想杀了对方
Looks like they're trying to kill each other.
从某个角度来看
That's one perspective.
看来这下子事情更不好处理了
Well, that makes things more complicated.
是啊
Yeah.
我们该怎么办?
What are we gonna do?
我们接受事实
We accept it.
明天我去和杜说  你去告诉山姆
Tomorrow I tell Dee, you tell Sam.
就那样做吗?
Just like that?
就是那样
Just like that.
我不知道
I don't know.
听着  我们告诉他们我们的感受
You know, we tell them how we feel.
我们把想法都冲天喊出来
We shout it to the skies.
是嘛
Yeah.
是啊  是啊  对
Yeah. Yeah, right.
什么  你不相信我会那样做吗?
What, you don't think I will?
嗯
Mmm-mmm.
李！
Lee!
我是李·阿达玛
My name is Lee Adama!
我爱卡拉·瑟瑞丝!
And I love Kara Thrace!
别太激动啦
Come down.
呵呵  又不会有人听到
What? What, it's not like anybody will hear,
我们在你的森林小木屋里  不是吗？
we're in your cabin in the forest, right?
我爱卡拉·瑟瑞丝
I love Kara Thrace!
不管谁他妈的知道我都不在乎!
And I don't care who frakking knows!
噢  你疯了 过来躺下
Oh, you're crazy. Get down.
来吧  除非你也站起来喊
Well, come on. I'm not going to stop
否则我不会停下的
until you get up and do it, too.
我办不到
I can't.
我会...好吧  再来一次
I'm gonna... Okay, here we go again.
李·阿达玛
Lee Adama...
好了好了
Okay, okay, okay. Okay.
好
Okay.
卡...
Ka...
卡拉·瑟瑞丝爱李·阿达玛!
Kara Thrace loves Lee Adama!
起来 星芭 起来 你能行的
Get up! Starbuck, get up! You can do this.
早上好  上将
Good morning, Admiral.
你看上去精神不错啊
You look like you had a good time.
是啊  参加了几个派对
Yeah, it was some party.
噢  这个早上也不寻常啊
Yeah, well, it's been a hell of a morning, too.
你错过了精彩的部分
You missed all the excitement.
为什么?  上面出了什么问题吗？
Why? Is it problems upstairs?
不
No.
不 是好事情 卡拉结婚了
No, good things. Kara got married.
相信吗?
You believe that?
什么?
What?
嗯  大概一个小时之前
Yeah, about an hour ago.
她自己找了个牧师 婚礼在河边举行的
Found herself a priest, went down by the river and got married.
你没事吧?
You okay?
你能相信吗?
ADAMA: Can you believe that?
她理应得到他
Well, she deserves that man.
我们都应该得到幸福
We all deserve to be happy.
我已经同意她离开舰队 跟泰罗尔和凯莉一起
I also gave her permission to muster out, along with Tyrol and Cally.
还有其他几个人  所以…
A few of the others, so...
我们得确保没有大规模的离职
We have to ask to make sure there's no mass exodus.
嘿  伙计!你听到消息了吗?
Hey, man. Did you hear the news?
我们结婚了 我们结婚了!
We're hitched. We got married.
你能相信吗?
Can you believe it?
不  不  我无法相信
No. No, I can't believe it.
是啊 太不可思议了 她过来我这儿  把我叫醒
Yeah. You know, it was crazy. She comes down and she wakes me up,
突然提出结婚  然后把我拽到牧师那里
she pops the question, she drags me down to the priest,
然后  哇  一眨眼间  我们结婚了
and bang! Like that. We're married.
这么说是你的主意
So it was your idea.
没错 是我的主意
Yeah. It was my idea.
你俩是不是需要点时间单独聊聊
SAM: Do you guys want a minute to, you know, talk?
祝贺你  山姆
Congratulations, Sam.
谢谢
Yeah.
祝好运
And good luck.
你们需要这个
You're gonna need it.
我出去了
I'm out of here.
我想你
I missed you.
我也想你
I missed you, too.